<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>api on Desmond Tuiyot</title>
    <link>/tags/api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in api on Desmond Tuiyot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandwidth API</title>
      <link>/notes/bandwidth-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/bandwidth-api/</guid>
      <description>Messaging 101About Bandwidth
It is a CPaaS provider - this is short for Communications Platforms as a Service - and it is the only CPaaS provider with its own national CLEC?? networkBillions of messages every month and 52m numbers on their networkWhat is a text message?
It’s not any of those received from WhatsApp, GroupMe, or Messenger, or any other app like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Twilio API for WhatsApp</title>
      <link>/notes/twilio-whatsapp-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/twilio-whatsapp-api/</guid>
      <description>Twilio API for WhatsApp Python QuickstartWe want to send and receive messages with WhatsApp using the Twilio API for WhatsAppWe’ll be usingTwilio Sandbox for WhatsAppPythonThe Twilio Python Twilio Helper LibraryFlaskSign Up for Twilio and Activate the SandboxFirst, sign up for a twilio account hereNext, sign into your account and activate the Twilio Sandbox for WhatsAppIn order to send messages in production, you have to wait for WhatsApp to approve your account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST APIs - Theory</title>
      <link>/notes/rest-apis-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/rest-apis-theory/</guid>
      <description>RESTful Service Best PracticesWhat is REST?REST Quick TipsDefinitionsIdempotentAn idempotent operation is one which produces the same result if executed one or multiple times.In the case of methods and subroutine calls, it could mean that they have no side effects (see Safety definition below)For those that have side effects, idempotence means that once the method is called initially and state changes, that modified state remains the same over repeated calls to itIn the context of RESTful services, clients can make the same call repeatedly, producing the same results/side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>